1801 E 12<sup>th</sup> ST (440)3902347 Cleveland, OH-44114 Paraggupta3.1@gmail.com

# **PARAG GUPTA**

www.github.com/paragcsu

www.linkedin.com/in/paragcsu/

#### **SUMMARY**

Individual with M.S in Computer and Information Science. Seeking for the position of Software/UI/Front-End Developer to apply my 3 years of experience in developing designs, test, and code; debugging programs to real problems, and adding value to the business

### **EDUCATION**

### Cleveland, OH Cleveland State University

Jan 2017-Dec 2018

- Masters: Computer and Information Science (GPA:3.49)
- Programming Coursework: Database, Network, Web Technologies

# Dehradun, India DIT University Aug 2010-May 2014

- Bachelors: Information Technology (GPA:3.5)
- Programming Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms

### **SKILLS**

Language C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS || Framework AngularJS, Asp.Net, Git, NodeJS, Bootstrap || Library jQuery, JSON, MVC || Database MySql || OS Linux, Windows || Other Tech WordPress, SEO, Azure, Project Management, MS Access, Adobe Dreamwork

### **EXPERIENCE**

# IT Intern Tucker Ellis LLC (Cleveland,OH) May 2018-Aug 2018

- Developed and implemented a JavaScript based learning platform that allows employees of the organization to easily undergo compliance training
- Improved network infrastructure efficiency by writing SQL Queries on Lansweeper editor

# **Software Analyst**

# Globallogic Technologies (New Delhi)

June 2014-Dec 2016

**Client:** Google Shopping Pittsburg

 Performed front-end development using HTML5 and CSS3 technique, backed by jQuery and other JavaScript framework to enable optimum user experience throughout the shopping site

Client: Globallogic, Ukraine (in house)

- Worked on a platform for collecting, accessing and managing patient and performance data from multiple client's devices
- Developed and designed UI for a database of customer's health and created secure login for members
- Created ASP.NET web forms containing C# code for business and data access logics

### **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

Personal Website: parag.azurewebsites.net/gupta/home.html (for additional information and projects)

### **University Student Portal**

Developed an Asp.Net application with C# as programming language and Microsoft SQL Server as backend while using Bootstrap to enhance UI. In this portal, Students can add, drop courses and pay fees and the account of a student gets calculated based on the number of courses enrolled.

### **Catering Website**

Gather functional and non-functional requirements and designed UML diagram, ER-diagram and class diagram for the system and developed an entire database.

# **RECOGIZATIONS**

- Certified by GOOGLE for the key contribution in the Google Shopping Project
- Certified by Hewlett Packard for attending 4 months of training on Linux Scripting and Software Architecture
- Certified by Microsoft for attending Microsoft Web Camp

I hereby declare that all the information mentioned above is correct and factual to best of my knowledge